[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
as you all know I've published around
seven YouTube videos covering basic
concepts of tricentistoska
by now you are very much familiar with
all the concepts that are required to
start test case automation by using
latest version Tasker so this is our
lesson 8
where I'm gonna teach you the initial
step
that is required to automate test cases
for automating the test cases by using
task we need to follow the series of
steps
I'm gonna teach you in detail in couple
of next sessions
to automate the test cases what are all
the steps that we need to follow to
complete test case automation of your
manual test cases
so this is lesson eight where I'm gonna
teach you the first step
where we'll be creating a test case
structure by using test case module in
Tasker 16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay so to create test case structure in
Tosca first we need to navigate around
the test case section
so in this session I'm going to teach
you the navigation of your test case
section
and then we are going to Define and
create the folder structure for test
case creation that reflects your
business workflow
so I'm going to take you an example and
I'm going to teach you creation of the
folder structure for that particular use
case
and also elements containing the
sequence information that means the test
case structure nothing but the elements
that contains the sequence of the
information
and to create test cases
we need to
actually call the modules that we
created in earlier sessions I already
explained you how to create the modules
right so the modules are related to
technical information and the test cases
are related to business information so
we will be creating test cases by using
the modules that we already created
okay and also we need to have a proper
naming convention while creating test
cases or test case folder structure
so we and also we need to use the three
approval stages stages while creating
the test cases that means when you are
when you start creating the test case
you will be changing the Status as
planned in Tasker and then once you
start progressing in the test case
structure or creation of the test case
you will be changing the Status to in
work
so once the then once we complete test
case creation we'll be changing the
Status to completed
okay so this session is mostly
concentrated on the test case folder
structure creation so in the subsequent
sessions I'm gonna teach you other steps
so that we can complete test case
automation
fully
so now let's jump onto the system and
see how can we create test case
structure by using Tasker latest version
16.
okay so first let me explain you what is
the test case that we are going to
automate
in today's session and we are going to
carry forward
the automation of this test case in the
upcoming couple of sessions okay
so as I explained you so test case
Automation in trycent
is
involved with
five to six
sequence of steps I'm gonna teach you
each step
clearly
with an example so that you can
understand how to automate your test
case okay so in this session
I'm gonna teach you how to first step of
your test case automation where you will
be creating a test case structure right
so I already explained you what does
this test case structure in my previous
slide so now let's understand what is
the test case that we are going to
automate okay so here this is as I
explained you in my previous sessions
I'm gonna use demo webshop it's a
website provided by try centers okay so
our test case is user need to login
with valid credentials
once he logins with valid credentials
you he need to order an item
what is ordering an item okay so first
we will be logging
by using a user
and then order the product
so let me order apparels and shoes
so please remember the sequence of the
business flow basically business
information are the sequence of the
process flow that we are talking here
okay that really helps in automating
your test case
so now what I'm doing I'm ordering the
product by clicking on the add to code
I'm ordering blue jeans
once I ordered the product now I need to
start checkout process how
go to shopping cart
and then
agree with the terms of service
and then click on checkout so this is
your start checkout process and then
checkout process so start checkout just
now we did and now what is the process
to complete your checkout that is
provide your billing address
and then select your shipping address
and then select your shipping method so
this I already explained in my previous
session okay select your shipping method
and then you have to select your payment
method cash credit card etc etc and then
you need to
see the payment information
and then you click on continue
here
and next step is see we just ordered the
product
started the checkout
and we completed checkout process
now what is the next step verification
of the prices so I need to verify
what is the shipping cost
what is the payment method additional
fee what is my total cost and what is my
quantity right so verification of the
prices is next step
once that is done
I need to click on confirmation that is
confirmation step
what is the confirmation step click on
confirmation and then see if you get the
order number or not
right and what is our next step is
verification of success you need to
verify if the order has been
successfully processed and then you got
the order number
okay so what are all the steps we it
involves the test case involves first
login
order product
start checkout
checkout process
verification of prices
confirmation
and verification of success
so these are all the sequence of actions
that I need to automate
to automate my entire test case
so now for this we need to create a
folder structure in
foreign
I have already explained you a different
sections of modules requirements
execution test cases right I already
explained in my previous session
I would recommend you guys to visit
previous session to understand more
about current session okay so now
first
automate your test case you need to
create a test case structure okay so for
that first let me so this is my test
case section so which is in blue and
green color Okay blue color basically
the blue color section is test case
section okay I am in test case section
first let me create right click on the
test case the main test case folder
and then create a folder
this is our eighth session correct so I
want to create a folder called zero
eight
sorry say okay zero eight
in work okay
let's
under this folder I want to create
another folder right click on the folder
and click on create folder
the name name this as session
sorry session 0 8
test case
structure so we are creating test Square
structure structure that's why I'm
naming the test case folder as a test
case structure
okay what is our test case
keeping cost basically what we are doing
we are actually verifying the shipping
cost and then successful message right I
want to create a test case now in this
folder see naming Convention of your
folder structure are the folders and the
test cases are very very important okay
create right click and this is your
folder I want to create a test case so
this is the symbol of your test case the
round circle with arrow okay create test
case
and name this as
shipping
costs
okay
so if you see here this is my test case
okay and now you need to navigate to
test cases how you just in the left side
this is your high level work structure
correct double click on this
and the right side is where you will be
planning or you will be writing your
test steps okay so now as soon as you
create your test case the work state
needs to be changed see if you see by
default work state is planned because
now I started working on this particular
test case mark this as in work I
explained you the states of your test
cases in my previous slide okay now my
test case is in the work right I'm
working on this test case
here under this test case I need to
create test step
folder structure so this is my test case
structure test case folder structure
once I create a test case you need to
create test step folder structure okay
right click let me create three folders
my first
the step folder structure is
precondition
and then my second folder is a process
actual process
and then the third folder is
post condition
right so I created the folder structure
of my test tips
under this process let's expand to the
left side okay under this process I want
to create six different folders
okay so for that you just click on
process folder in the left pane so that
the process will be opening in your
right pin okay now I need to create
six different folders
right click so I explained you the
process where the login process right
login order
product
start checkout right so that is what I'm
going to create now
so first what is the process
first I need to create or I need to
order the product right order
product
once I order the product
what is my test case flow start checkout
start
checkout
once you start the checkout
check out process need to complete
correct so check out where you'll be
entering your shipping method payment
method and all these things check out
process
so checkout process is done and then you
need to verify the prices
so right click again
create folder
verification of prices
right
once that is done
my next is confirmation I have to
confirm the order right confirmation
okay
once confirmation is done
you need to verify the successful order
placement correct right click
create folder
verification
of success
verification of success
right so now
I have created six different folders
under process so if you go to test case
now
if you see here
this is my entire test case structure my
test case is
some test case like called test case
structure under this I have created one
test case called shipping costs
under this test case I have created
three main folders
precondition process post condition
and then under process I have defined
the
flow of the process order product start
checkout checkout process verification
of prices confirmation verification of
success so that means now this test case
is a meaningful test case
this defines my business flow
I created the test case structure with a
business View
right so for this session that is it so
in the next session so once you create
your test case structure now you need a
technical I already explained about
modules right where
we store the technical information of
your system under test
and this is your
test case structure so now we need to
combine the technical information with
this case structure and provide your
business information or the test data
that is required to steer your test case
right so our first step of our
test case automation is done
so in the next session I am going to
teach you our next step to complete our
s case automation by using task okay so
if you have any queries
provide your comments in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries
thank you
[Music]